barcodetopc.com 2019-06-11

# Privacy Policy - Barcode to PC

**Updated Dec 10, 2018**

At Barcode to PC, we care about the privacy of your data and are committed to protecting it. This Privacy Policy  
explains what information we collect about you and why, what we do with that information, and how we handle  
that information. We’ll also explain what choices you have with respect to the information. 

## Applicability Of This Privacy Policy

This Privacy Policy applies to Barcode to PC desktop and mobile applications (collectively, the “Products”), Barcode to PC.com  
and other Barcode to PC websites (collectively, the “Sites”) and other interactions (e.g., customer service inquiries,  
user conferences, etc.) you may have with Barcode to PC. If you do not agree with the terms, do not access or use the  
Products, Sites or any other aspect of Barcode to PC’s business. 

This policy applies to the Company’s employees, contractors and officers.

The Company has a contract with all Data Processors that it uses in compliance with Article 28 & Article 29  
of the GDPR, and ensures that all Data Processors are compliant with Data Protection Legislation.

The policy does not apply to third party services. Where third party services are used, and the third party is  
not a Data Processor, no Relevant Data (as defined below) is shared with them, or the Relevant Data has been  
anonymised such that the GDPR does not apply. Information collected by third parties is governed by their  
privacy practices. We encourage you to learn about the privacy practices of those third parties.

In addition, a separate agreement governs delivery, access and use of the Products (the “User Agreement”).

This policy applies to Relevant Data received and processed only.

## Definitions

Capitalized terms used in this Policy and not otherwise defined shall have the meanings provided below:

_**Products:**_

  * Barcode to PC server
  * Barcode to PC

_**Relevant Data**_ – Personal Data and Special Categories of Data are the Relevant Data covered by this  
policy and as defined in the Data Protection Legislation.

_**Personal Data**_ – any information relating to an identified or identifiable natural person.

_**Special Categories of Data**_ – Personal data revealing racial or ethnic origin, political opinions,  
religious or philosophical beliefs, or trade union membership, genetic data, biometric data and data concerning  
health or a person’s sex life or sexual orientation.

**_Processing/Processed_** – any operation on personal data, whether automated or not.

## Information We Collect and Receive

When you interact with our Sites and Products, we collect Information that, alone or in combination with other  
data, could be used to identify you (Personal Data). Some of the Information we collect is stored in a manner  
that cannot be linked back to you (Non-Personal Data).

### Payments Information

Payments information provided by you via the Sites will be stored and processed by FastSpring.com and  
any other third party service providers as designated by us from time to time. We will collect certain  
information on the Sites required for FastSpring.com and such third party services providers to  
process payments, including credit / debit card numbers, security numbers and other related payment  
information. All such information is subject to the privacy policy of FastSpring.com (available here  
<https://fastspring.com/privacy> ) or any  
other third party service provider as applicable.

### Other Information

Barcode to PC also collects, generates and/or receives Other Information:

### Usage Information

Certain data about the devices you use to connect with Barcode to PC and your use of the Sites and/or Products are  
automatically logged in our systems, including:

  * Location information. This is the geographic area where you use your computer and mobile devices (as  
indicated by an Internet Protocol [IP] address or similar identifier) when interacting with our Sites  
and/or Products.
  * Log data. As with most websites and technology services delivered over the internet, our servers  
automatically collect data when you access or use our Sites and/or Products and record it in log files.  
This log data may include the IP address, browser type and settings, the date and time of use, information  
about browser configuration, language preferences, and cookie data.
  * Products and Sites Specific Data. This is information about the Barcode to PC Sites and/or Products you use and  
how you use them. We may also obtain data from our third-party partners and service providers to analyze  
how users use our Sites and/or Products. For example, we will know how many users access a specific page on  
the Site and which links they clicked on. We use this aggregated information to better understand and  
optimize the Site.
  * Device information. These are data from your computer or mobile device, such as the type of hardware and  
software you are using (for example, your operating system and browser type), as well as unique device  
identifiers for devices that are using Barcode to PC Products.

### Cookies

Barcode to PC uses cookies and similar technologies in our Sites and Services that help us collect Other Information.  
The Sites and Services may also include cookies and similar tracking technologies of third parties, which may  
collect Other Information about you via the Sites and Services and across other websites and online services.  
For more details about how we use these technologies, please see our  
Cookie Policy.

### Third Party Data

Barcode to PC may receive data about Site visitors, marketing campaigns and other matters related to our business from  
affiliates and subsidiaries, our partners or others that we use to make our own information better or more  
useful. This data may be combined with Other Information we collect and might include aggregate level data,  
such as which IP addresses correspond to zip codes or countries. Or it might be more specific: for example, how  
well an online marketing or email campaign performed.

### Additional Information Provided to Barcode to PC

We receive Other Information when submitted to our Sites or if you participate in a focus group, contest,  
activity or event, apply for a job, request support, interact with our social media accounts or otherwise  
communicate with Barcode to PC.

## Collection Information from Children

Barcode to PC does not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of 13. If we determine we  
have collected personal information from a child younger than 13 years of age, we will take reasonable measures  
to remove that information from our systems. If you are under the age of 13, please do not submit any personal  
information through the Site and/or Products. We encourage parents and legal guardians to monitor their  
children’s Internet usage and to help enforce this Policy by instructing their children never to provide  
personal information through the Sites and/or Products without their permission.

## Using Your Information by Barcode to PC

We use, process, and store your information as necessary to perform our contract with you and for our legitimate  
business interests, in operating our Sites, Products, Services, and business including:

  * to help us administer our Sites and/or Products, authenticate users for security purposes, provide  
personalized user features and access, process transactions, conduct research, develop new features, and  
improve the features, algorithms, and usability of our Sites and/or Products;
  * As required by applicable law, legal process or regulation.
  * to calculate aggregate statistics on the number of unique devices using our Sites and/or Products;
  * to send emails and other communications. We may send you service, technical and other administrative  
emails, messages and other types of communications. We may also contact you to inform you about changes in  
our Products, our Products offerings, and important Products-related notices, such as security and fraud  
notices. These communications are considered part of the Products and you may not opt out of them. In  
addition, we sometimes send emails about new product features, promotional communications or other news  
about Barcode to PC. We will only send you marketing information if you consent to us;
  * for billing, account management and other administrative matters. Barcode to PC may need to contact you for  
invoicing, account management and similar reasons and we use account data to administer accounts and keep  
track of billing and payments.
  * to investigate and help prevent security issues, fraud and abuse.

If information is aggregated or de-identified so it is no longer reasonably associated with an identified or  
identifiable natural person, Barcode to PC may use it for any business purpose. 

## How We Share And Disclose Information

We only disclose Personal Data to third parties when:

  * We use service providers who assist us in meeting business operations needs, including hosting, delivering,  
and improving our Products. We also use service providers for specific services and functions, including  
email communication, customer support services, and analytics. These service providers may only access,  
process, or store Personal Data pursuant to our instructions and to perform their duties to us.
  * We have your explicit consent to share your Personal Data (if required).
  * We believe it is necessary to investigate potential violations of the Terms of Products, to enforce those  
Terms of Products, or where we believe it is necessary to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding  
illegal activities, suspected fraud, or potential threats against persons, property, or the systems on  
which we operate our Site and/or Products.
  * We determine that the access, preservation, or disclosure of your Personal Data is required by law to  
protect the rights, property, or personal safety of Barcode to PC and users of our Site and/or Products, or to  
respond to lawful requests by public authorities, including national security or law enforcement requests.
  * We need to do so in connection with a merger, acquisition, bankruptcy, reorganization, sale of some or all  
of our assets or stock, public offering of securities, or steps in consideration of such activities (e.g.,  
due diligence). In these cases some or all of your Personal Data may be shared with or transferred to  
another entity, subject to this Privacy Policy.
  * We may disclose Non-Personal Data publicly and to third parties – for example, in public reports about word  
usage, to partners under agreement with us, or as part of progress reports we may provide to users.

Barcode to PC does not share your Personal Data with third parties for the purpose of enabling them to deliver their  
advertisements to you.

Barcode to PC does not sell or rent your Personal Data.

**Third Parties’ Applications and Products**

Some third-party applications and services that work with us may ask for permission to access your information.  
Those applications will provide you with notice and request your consent in order to obtain such access or  
information. Please consider your selection of such applications and services, and your permissions, carefully.

Some third parties’ embedded content or plugins on our Sites and/or Products, such as Facebook “Like” buttons,  
may allow their operators to learn that you have visited the Sites, and they may combine this knowledge with  
other data they have collected about your visits to other websites or online services that can identify you.

Data collected by third parties through these apps and plugins is subject to each parties’ own policies. We  
encourage you to read those policies and understand how other companies use your data.

**E-mailing by Barcode to PC**

From time to time, we may want to contact you with information about product announcements, software updates,  
and special offers. We also may want to contact you with information about products and services from our  
business partners. 

We only send marketing communications to users with your prior consent.

All Barcode to PC account holders will continue to receive transactional messages related to our Products, even if you  
unsubscribe from promotional emails.

## Data storage, transfer, retention, and deletion

### Data Storage and Transfers

Information submitted to Barcode to PC will be transferred to, processed, and stored in the United States. When you use  
the Products on your computing device, user content you save will be stored locally on that device and synced  
with our servers. If you post or transfer any Information to or through our Sites and/or Products, you are  
agreeing to such information, including Personal Data and user content, being hosted and accessed in the United  
States.

### Duration of Information Storage

You can remove your Personal Data from Barcode to PC at any time by emailing us with the respective request: [support@barcodetopc.com](mailto:support@barcodetopc.com).  
However, we may keep some of your Personal Data for as long as reasonably necessary for our legitimate business  
interests, including fraud detection and prevention and to comply with our legal obligations including tax,  
legal reporting, and auditing obligations.

### Safeguards

When you give us personal information, we take steps to make sure that it’s treated securely.

Non-sensitive details (your email address etc.) are sent normally over the Internet, and this can never be  
guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, while we strive to protect your personal information, we cannot  
guarantee the security of any information you transmit to us, and you do so at your own risk. Once we receive  
your information, we make our best effort to ensure its security on our systems.

We use industry-standard encryption to protect your data in transit. This is commonly referred to as transport  
layer security (“TLS”) or secure socket layer (“SSL”) technology.

Once we receive your data, we protect it on our servers using a combination of technical, physical, and logical  
security safeguards. The security of the data stored locally in any of our Products installed on your computing  
device requires that you make use of the security features of your device. We recommend that you take the  
appropriate steps to secure all computing devices that you use in connection with our Site and Products.

The Company takes the security of your data very seriously and works to protect your data from loss, misuse and  
unauthorised access or disclosure.

All staff and officers who handle Relevant Data are aware of this policy and have been given training in how to  
correctly collect, process, store and delete data. The Company holds a log of when staff training was  
undertaken and updates it on an annual basis.

### Data Breaches

All breaches will be reported to the relevant supervisory authority within 72 hours, unless the data was  
anonymised or encrypted or if it has a particularly high risk.

Breaches of this policy by staff, contractors, officers of the Company will be dealt with under the Company’s  
grievance and disciplinary policy and may lead to a disciplinary sanction.

If Barcode to PC learns of a security system breach, we may attempt to notify you and provide information on protective  
steps, if available, through the email address that you have provided to us or by posting a notice on the Site.  
Depending on where you live, you may have a legal right to receive such notices in writing.

## Your Rights

Barcode to PC uses, processes, and stores Personal Data, as necessary to perform our contract with you, and based on  
our legitimate interests in order to provide the Products and Services. We rely on your consent to process  
Personal Data to send promotional emails and to place cookies on your devices. In some cases, Barcode to PC may  
process Personal Data pursuant to legal obligation or to protect your vital interests or those of another  
person.

Individuals located in the European Economic Area (EEA) have certain rights in respect to their personal  
information, including the right to access, correct, or delete Personal Data we process through your use of the  
Sites, Software, and/or Products. If you’re a user based in the EEA, you can:

  * Have your Personal Data corrected or deleted. You may ask us to correct information you think is inaccurate  
or completely delete all information that we hold about you by emailing:  
[support@barcodetopc.com](mailto:support@barcodetopc.com).
  * Access your Personal Data report by submitting a request at support@barcodetopc.com. This report will include  
the Personal Data we have about you, provided to you in a structured, commonly used, and portable format.
  * Object to us processing your Personal Data. It is your right to lodge an objection to the processing of  
your personal data by emailing: [support@barcodetopc.com](mailto:support@barcodetopc.com) if you feel the  
“ground relating to your particular situation” apply. The only reasons we will be able to deny your request  
is if we can show compelling legitimate grounds for the processing, which override your interest, rights  
and freedoms, or the processing is for the establishment, exercise or defence of a legal claims.
  * You can ask us to stop using your Personal Data, including when we use your Personal Data to send you  
marketing emails. We only send marketing communications to users located in the EEA with your prior  
consent, and you may withdraw your consent at any time by clicking the “unsubscribe” link found within  
Barcode to PC emails and changing your contact preferences. Please note you will continue to receive transactional  
messages related to our Products, even if you unsubscribe from marketing emails.
  * Complain to a regulator. If you’re based in the EEA and think that we haven’t complied with data protection  
laws, you have a right to lodge a complaint with your local supervisory authority.

## Changes to our Privacy Policy

This privacy policy was last updated on Dec 10 2018 and this version is in line with the new GDPR guidelines.

We may need to update this Policy to keep pace with changes in our Sites, Products, and Services, our business,  
and laws applicable to us and you. We will, however, always maintain our commitment to respect your privacy. We  
will notify you of any material changes that impact your rights under this Policy by email (to your most  
recently provided email address) or post any other revisions to this Policy, along with their effective date,  
in an easy-to-find area of the Sites, so we recommend that you periodically check back here to stay informed of  
any changes. Please note that your continued use of Barcode to PC after any change means that you agree with, and  
consent to be bound by, the new Policy. If you disagree with any changes in this Policy and do not wish your  
information to be subject to it, you will need to stop using the Sites and/or Products.

## Contact us

You may contact us with any questions relating to this Privacy Policy by e-mailing: [support@barcodetopc.com](mailto:support@barcodetopc.com)
